Guide to the New-York Historical Society John Watts DePeyster Publication Fund Records 1857-1982 NYHS-RG 10
New-York Historical Society
- Series II. Correspondence, 1857-1982; 12.13 Linear feet
  - Orders. Volume 30 (5 folders), 1905 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 1-5)
  - Orders. Volume 31 (5 folders), 1906-1907 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 1-5)
  - Orders. Volumes 32, 33 (8 folders), 1907-1908 (Offsite-box 25, Folder 1-8)
  - Orders. Volumes 34-37 (10 folders), 1908, 1910 (Offsite-box 26, Folder 1-10)
  - Orders. Volumes 39-44 (9 folders), 1913-1914 (Offsite-box 27, Folder 1-9)
  - Orders. Volumes 50-53 (8 folders), 1919, 1922 (Offsite-box 28, Folder 1-8)
  - Orders. Volumes 54-58 (8 folders), 1923, 1925 (Offsite-box 29, Folder 1-8)
  - Orders. Volumes 59-61 (9 folders), 1927-1928 (Offsite-box 30, Folder 1-9)
  - Exchanges. American Academy of Arts & Sciences, 1873-1976 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 1)
  - Exchanges. American Jewish Historical Society, 1931-1972 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 2)
  - Exchanges. American Philosophical Society, 1857-1967 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 3)
  - Exchanges. British Museum, 1924-1972 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 4)
  - Exchanges. Bureau of American Ethnology (Smithsonian), 1913-1944 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 5)
  - Exchanges. Canada Department of Agriculture Library, 1925-1972 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 6)
  - Exchanges. Canada, Russia and Other Foreign, 1922-1936 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 7)
  - Exchanges. Cincinnati Historical Society (Ohio Historical & Philosophical Society), 1932-1972 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 8)
  - Exchanges. Connecticut Historical Society, 1910-1965 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 9)
  - Exchanges. Georgia Historical Society, 1870-1961 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 10)
  - Exchanges. Historical Society of Delaware, 1931-1955 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 11)
  - Exchanges. Historical Society of Pennsylvania, 1857-1961 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 12)
  - Exchanges. Holland Society of New York, 1913-1972 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 13)
  - Exchanges. Illinois State Historical Library, 1912-1961 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 14)
  - Exchanges. Iowa State Department of History & Archives, 1954 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 15)
  - Exchanges. Johns Hopkins University Library, 1916-1976 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 16)
  - Exchanges. Massachusetts Historical Society, 1857-1972 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 17)
  - Exchanges. Michigan State Library, 1931-1954 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 18)
  - Exchanges. Minnesota Historical Society, 1931-1961 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 19)
  - Exchanges. Municipal Reference Library (New York), 1932-1955 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 20)
  - Exchanges. National Archives (U.S.), 1937-1965 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 21)
  - Exchanges. National Museum of Canada, 1932-1953 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 22)
  - Exchanges. Nebraska State Historical Society, 1931-1961 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 23)
  - Exchanges. New England Historic Genealogical Society, 1857-1961 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 24)
  - Exchanges. New Jersey State Library, 1919-1954 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 25)
  - Exchanges. New York Academy of Medicine, 1939-1972 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 26)
  - Exchanges. New York State Archives & History Division, 1911-1932 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 27)
  - Exchanges. New York State Historical Association, 1931-1965 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 28)
  - Exchanges. New York State Library, 1857-1961 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 29)
  - Exchanges. Northwestern University Library, 1938-1967 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 30)
  - Exchanges. Nova Scotia Historical Society, 1932-1978 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 31)
  - Exchanges. Ohio Historical Society, 1932-1975 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 32)
  - Exchanges. Ontario Historical Society, 1914-1955 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 33)
  - Exchanges. Oregon Historical Society, 1931-1961 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 34)
  - Exchanges. Public Archives of Canada, 1930-1962 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 35)
  - Exchanges. Rhode Island Historical Society, 1931-1961 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 36)
  - Exchanges. Rhodes House Library, 1931-1965 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 37)
  - Exchanges. Rochester Historical Society, 1932-1973 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 38)
  - Exchanges. Smithsonian Institution, 1928-1963 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 39)
  - Exchanges. Stanford University Libraries, 1934-1962 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 40)
  - Exchanges. State Historical Society of Iowa, 1911-1961 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 41)
  - Exchanges. State Historical Society of Missouri, 1931-1975 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 42)
  - Exchanges. State Historical Society of Wisconsin, 1872-1961 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 43)
  - Exchanges. Staten Island Historical Society, 1954-1961 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 44)
  - Exchanges. Tennessee State Library & Archives, 1915-1968 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 45)
  - Exchanges. Texas State Historical Association, 1909-1940 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 46)
  - Exchanges. University of London, Institute of Historical Research, 1936-1965 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 47)
  - Exchanges. University of Mississippi, 1933-1954 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 48)
  - Exchanges. University of North Carolina, 1939-1975 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 49)
  - Exchanges. Vermont Historical Society, 1872-1932 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 50)
  - Exchanges. Virginia Historical Society, 1870-1961 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 51)
  - Exchanges. Virginia State Library, 1931-1961 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 52)
  - Exchanges. Western Reserve Historical Society, 1870-1975 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 53)
  - Exchanges. William L. Clements Library, 1932-1961 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 54)
  - Exchanges. Wyoming State Archives & Historical Department, 1972 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 55)
  - Exchanges (Obsolete). Academy of Commerce (Poland), 1939 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 56)
  - Exchanges (Obsolete). American Antiquarian Society, 1919-1932 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 57)
  - Exchanges (Obsolete). American Geographical Society, 1931-1944 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 58)
  - Exchanges (Obsolete). American Irish Historical Society, 1924-1937 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 59)
  - Exchanges (Obsolete). Amherst College, 1981 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 60)
  - Exchanges (Obsolete). Army War College, 1932-1937 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 61)
  - Exchanges (Obsolete). Boston Public Library, 1869-1937 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 62)
  - Exchanges (Obsolete). Bryn Mawr College, 1916-1932 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 63)
  - Exchanges (Obsolete). Canada, 1918-1946 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 1)
    Includes Antiquarian & Numismatic Society and Bibliotheque Saint-Sulpice.
  - Exchanges (Obsolete). Clark University, 1946 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 2)
  - Exchanges (Obsolete). Colby College, 1941 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 3)
  - Exchanges (Obsolete). Columbia Historical Society, 1931-1932 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 4)
  - Exchanges (Obsolete). Department of State (U.S.), 1914-1944 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 5)
  - Exchanges (Obsolete). Filson Club, 1932 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 6)
  - Exchanges (Obsolete). Fort Washington Historical Society, 1939 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 7)
  - Exchanges (Obsolete). Historical Society of Western Pennsylvania, 1931-1932 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 8)
  - Exchanges (Obsolete). Kansas State Historical Society, 1931-1954 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 9)
  - Exchanges (Obsolete). Kings County Historical Society, 1932 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 10)
  - Exchanges (Obsolete). Legislative Library (Canada), 1937-1941 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 11)
  - Exchanges (Obsolete). Library of Congress, 1876-1944 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 12)
  - Exchanges (Obsolete). Literary & Historical Society (Canada), 1932 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 13)
  - Exchanges (Obsolete). Louisiana Historical Society, 1932-1954 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 14)
  - Exchanges (Obsolete). Lynn Historical Society, 1931-1953 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 15)
  - Exchanges (Obsolete). Maine Historical Society, 1931-1932 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 16)
  - Exchanges (Obsolete). Maine State Library, 1950-1953 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 17)
  - Exchanges (Obsolete). Mark Skinner Library, 1931-1932 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 18)
  - Exchanges (Obsolete). Maryland Historical Society, 1869-1961 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 19)
  - Exchanges (Obsolete). Massachusetts State Library, 1873-1932 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 20)
  - Exchanges (Obsolete). Mississippi Valley Historical Association, 1931-1932 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 21)
  - Exchanges (Obsolete). Monmouth County Historical Association, 1932-1944 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 22)
  - Exchanges (Obsolete). New Hampshire Historical Society, 1910-1932 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 23)
  - Exchanges (Obsolete). New Rochelle Public Library, 1919-1932 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 24)
  - Exchanges (Obsolete). New York Genealogical & Biographical Society, 1932 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 25)
  - Exchanges (Obsolete). North Dakota State Historical Society, 1941 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 26)
  - Exchanges (Obsolete). Oklahoma Historical Society, 1932 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 27)
  - Exchanges (Obsolete). Princeton Theological Seminary, 1941-1952 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 28)
  - Exchanges (Obsolete). Public Archives of Nova Scotia, 1933-1978 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 29)
  - Exchanges (Obsolete). Puerto Rico, 1916-1935 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 30)
    Includes Academia Puertorriquena de la Historia and Government of Porto Rico Insular Library.
  - Exchanges (Obsolete). Royal Historical Society, 1941 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 31)
  - Exchanges (Obsolete). Schenectady County Historical Society, 1941 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 32)
  - Exchanges (Obsolete). Society for the Propagation of the Gospel in Foreign Parts, 1939 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 33)
  - Exchanges (Obsolete). Society of Colonial Wars in the State of New York, 1931-1941 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 34)
  - Exchanges (Obsolete). Society of the Cincinnati, 1938 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 35)
  - Exchanges (Obsolete). South Dakota Department of History, 1931-1932 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 36)
  - Exchanges (Obsolete). Staten Island Institute of Arts & Sciences, 1931-1944 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 37)
  - Exchanges (Obsolete). Union College, 1931-1932 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 38)
  - Exchanges (Obsolete). Universitetsbiblioteket Uppsala (Sweden), 1931-1965 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 39)
  - Exchanges (Obsolete). University of California, 1931-1932 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 40)
  - Exchanges (Obsolete). University of Colorado, 1912-1944 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 41)
  - Exchanges (Obsolete). University of Vermont, 1931-1955 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 42)
  - Exchanges (Obsolete). Wellesley College Library, 1931-1944 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 43)
  - Exchanges (Obsolete). West Virginia Historical Society, 1931 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 44)
  - Exchanges (Obsolete). Wyoming Historical & Geological Society, 1931-1932 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 45)
  - General Correspondence, 1858-1859 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 46)
    Includes letters from original Fund subscribers.
  - General Correspondence, 1865, 1868-1869 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 47)
  - General Correspondence, 1870-1872 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 48)
  - General Correspondence, 1873-1878 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 49)
  - General Correspondence, 1879 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 50)
  - General Correspondence, 1880 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 51)
  - General Correspondence, 1881 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 52)
  - General Correspondence, 1882 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 53)
  - General Correspondence, 1883 (Offsite-box 33, Folder 1)
  - General Correspondence, 1884-1889 (Offsite-box 33, Folder 2)
  - General Correspondence, 1905-1909 (Offsite-box 33, Folder 3)
  - General Correspondence, 1910-1919 (Offsite-box 33, Folder 4)
  - General Correspondence, 1920-1929 (Offsite-box 33, Folder 5)
  - General Correspondence, circa 1914-1922 (Offsite-box 33, Folder 6)
    Includes envelopes of returned and undelivered mail for announced volumes and notes on shareholders.
  - General Correspondence, 1930-1935 (Offsite-box 33, Folder 7)
    Includes correspondence concerning distribution of the Diary of William Dunlap, which was not a DePeyster Fund publication.
  - General Correspondence, 1936-1939 (Offsite-box 33, Folder 8)
  - General Correspondence, 1940-1942 (Offsite-box 33, Folder 9)
  - General Correspondence (Cadmus Book Shop Letters), 1932-1941 (Offsite-box 33, Folder 10)
    See also New-York Historical Society General Correspondence (NYHS-RG 2) for correspondence with Cadmus in the 1920s concerning various transfers of shares in the Fund (filed under "Ca" in that record group's alphabetically arranged correspondence).
  - [General Correspondence. Subscriber Letter Book], circa 1895-1937 (Volume RG10.11)
  - General Correspondence. Loose Papers from Letter Book, circa 1902-1932 (Offsite-box 33, Folder 11)
  - General Correspondence, 1943-1949 (Offsite-box 33, Folder 12)
  - General Correspondence, 1952-1953 (Offsite-box 33, Folder 13)
  - General Correspondence, 1965-1975 (Offsite-box 33, Folder 14)
    Includes the notices to shareholders of volumes published in this period.